http://www.daa.asn.au/about-DA/privacy-policy/

– Logout
Member Portal
Search
About usStrategic PlanOrganisational chartBoard of Directors and ExecutivePast PresidentsAnnual ReportReconciliationConstitution and By-lawsCelebrating Member AchievementsAwardsPrizesJosephine (Jo) Rogers AMResearch Grants and ScholarshipsFellows of DA and Advanced APDsProfessional AffiliationsPartnershipsPublic PoliciesAdvertising policiesAlliances and PartnershipsEndorsementMembership fees policyWebsite Link PolicyPrivacy PolicyMembershipWhat Dietitians DoDietitian or Nutritionist?Why Choose an Accredited Practising Dietitian?Your Rights and ResponsibilitiesWhere do Dietitians Work?Information for Healthcare ProfessionalsAPD RolesBecoming a Dietitian in AustraliaAustralian Dietetics Council (ADC)ADC PoliciesAccreditation of Dietetics Education ProgramsAccredited Dietetics Education ProgramsAccreditation Standards and ProcessesRecognition of Dietetic QualificationsDietetic Skills Recognition (DSR)Overseas educated dietitians – Assessment StageDietetic Skills Recognition CriteriaEnglish Language ProficiencyOverseas educated dietitians – Examination stageAppeals ProcessMutual RecognitionMutual Recognition – New ZealandMutual recognition profilesNew Zealand FAQsSkills Migration AssessmentFeesFAQsMembership of DAMaintaining Professional StandardsAccredited Practising Dietitian ProgramHow to Join the APD ProgramDietitian Scope of PracticeNational Competency Standards for DietitiansDietetic Credentialing CouncilProfessional Standards and Code of ConductSupporting Best Practice in DieteticsRegister of Accredited Practising DietitiansAPD registration number FAQExpelled or Suspended MembersDismissal of Ms Jennifer Elliott as a DA memberHow to make a complaintVoice of DietitiansNews RoomMedia ReleasesHot TopicsDietitians Making NewsOur SpokespeopleEditorialChallenging MisinformationDA’s approach to social mediaAdvocacyCall for a New National Nutrition PolicySubmissions2019 Submissions2018 Submissions2017 Submissions2016 Submissions2015 SubmissionsPosition StatementsJoint Position StatementsAdvocacy lettersSmart Eating for a Healthier YouSmart Eating Fast FactsCOVID-19 tips and resourcesNutrition tips and advice during COVID-19Cooking during COVID-19Healthy EatingDietitians’ top (healthy) Christmas gift ideasHealthy eating on a budgetCan I drink alcohol?Health and Wellbeing of Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander peopleI’ve heard I need 2 serves of fruit & 5 serves of vegetables, but what is a serve?I’m tired all the time, should I try a detox diet?The low-down on Paleo – Welcome to our three part series on the Palaeolithic diet.How much exercise do I need to stay healthy?What’s the best type of fat for a healthy heart?Vegan diets: everything you need to knowVegetarian diets – the basicsBreakfast – how to eat brekkie like a boss!Australia’s Healthy Weight WeekThe Australian Dietary GuidelinesChildrenFive ways to help tackle fussy eatingShould we be concerned about a child’s weight?How can I prevent my child from becoming overweight?My child is overweight, what should I do?How can I get my child to eat more fruits and vegetables?What can I put in my child’s lunchbox?How much television can my children watch if I want them to be healthy?Can food additives affect my child’s behaviour?TeensPregnancyNutrition for pregnancyIs there a special diet I should follow while trying to get pregnant?What extra nutrients do I need in pregnancy?What do I need to eat if I’m breastfeeding?Why do pregnant and breastfeeding women need more iodine?Nourishing NutrientsPumping ironAnaemia: my doctor says I need more ironWhy do we need calcium?Carbohydrates – what you need to knowFat: to cut or not to cut, that is the questionWhere do I find saturated fats in foodThe ins and outs of unsaturated fatsShould I be worried about trans fats?All about plant sterols and stanols for cholesterol managementAll about proteinDietary fibre: key for a happy, healthy gutFolate: crucial for women under 50What are the current Nutrient Reference Values (NRVs)?Food and Food Products5 minutes with Matthew Evans – The gap between nourishment and pleasureFast facts: all about avocadosIs organic food better for my health?I don’t eat a lot of fruit and vegetables, should I take a supplement instead?What’s healthier: fresh, frozen or canned foods?Can I eat eggs if I want to be healthy?Are artificial sweeteners safe to eat?Extra Virgin Olive Oil – the latest updateIf I have high cholesterol, can I eat foods with cholesterol?Which type of milk should I drink?Which drinks are the best choice?Top take-away food tipsLegumes: what are they and how can I use them?Why dietitians are nuts about nutsThe facts on coconut oil – is it the best choice?Food waste – a bigger issue that you’d thinkFood LabelsHow are food products regulated in Australia?What are health claims and what do they mean?Making sense of the glycaemic indexWhat does low fat mean?What does low salt mean?MedicalWhat to eat to reduce your risk of gallstonesOrthorexia: The unhealthy side of healthy eatingFODMAPs and IBS: What’s the deal?Can I lower my blood pressure by following a healthy eating plan?How can what I eat improve high blood pressure?Eating less saltThe ins and outs of cholesterolCan I lower my cholesterol through dietary changes?What is coeliac disease?Dental health – looking after your teeth and gumsIs there a diet to prevent and treat cancer?Is there a diet to treat arthritis?The facts on overweight & obesity in AustraliaMy doctor has told me I have impaired glucose tolerance, what should I do?Diabetes – the basicsWhat is insulin resistance?What is metabolic syndrome?What can I do if I am worried that a friend has an eating disorder?What’s the difference between food allergy and food intolerance?Understanding food intolerance & sensitivityA guide to irritable bowel syndromeMy doctor said I’ve got diverticular disease, what should I eat?Helping to ease the pain of gout through dietUnderstanding lactose intoleranceAre you underweight?Is malnutrition an issue in Australia?Malnutrition – who is at risk and things to considerThings to consider with haemochromatosisWeight ManagementWeight loss goals other than the scalesSmart eating for weight managementHow to spot a dodgy weight loss dietAre carbohydrates fattening?How can I choose the right weight loss plan for me?How can I stay motivated to maintain a healthy diet for weight loss?What should I do to lose weight?I need to gain weight, what should I eat?Smart Eating RecipesEvents and MarketplaceCentre for Advanced LearningAged CareBariatric SurgeryCounsellingDiabetesEating DisordersFood Allergy and IntoleranceNutrition SupportPaediatricsSports NutritionPEN – Practice-based Evidence in Nutrition®Advertise with usFind a LocumPublications & ResourcesResources available for purchaseNutrition & Dietetics JournalEditorial BoardFor AuthorsFor ReviewersAssociate Editor CentreNutrition & Dietetics Journal AppLectures in Honour & Obituaries
Privacy Policy
This Privacy (“Policy”) covers the Dietitians Australia’s (‘DA’s’) collection, holding, use and disclosure of Personal Information.
Key Definitions
DA has adopted the definitions given to ‘Personal Information’ and ‘Sensitive Information’ as outlined in the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) (“the Privacy Act”). These are:
‘Personal Information’ means the information or an opinion (including information or an opinion forming part of a database), whether true or not, and whether recorded in a material form or not, about an individual whose identity is apparent, or can reasonably be ascertained, from the information or opinion.
‘Sensitive Information’ includes (but is not limited to) information or an opinion about an individual’s:
Racial or ethnic origin; or
Political opinions; or
Membership of a political association; or
Religious beliefs or affiliations; or
Philosophical beliefs; or
Membership of a profession or trade association; or
Membership of a trade union; or
Sexual preferences or practices; or
Criminal record
that is also Personal Information; or
Health information about an individual; or
Genetic information about an individual that is not otherwise health information.
What Personal Information do we collect?
The information we collect depends on the nature of your interactions with us. DA collects both Personal Information and non-personal information, including details about:
Our members, potential members, business associates and their personnel.
Allied health professionals, government agencies and professional bodies.
Our suppliers and their personnel.
Our employees, partners, contractors, former employees and former members.
Former prospective members, former business associates and their personnel.
The Personal Information we may collect and hold includes: name, postal address, email address, phone number, credit or debit card information, age, gender, username and password (if applicable), personal preferences, education and qualifications, testimonials, feedback and other information to assist DA in conducting our business, providing and marketing our services and meeting our legal obligations.
DA may collect additional information from its employees, such as tax file numbers.
DA may also collect Sensitive Information such as health information and information about an individual’s membership of professional associations.
DA may also collect and process non-personal information provided by your browser when you visit our website. This may include the website you came from, your location information, IP address and the time and date of access.
How do we collect your Personal Information?
DA will collect Personal Information from you in several ways.
Directly. For example, while using our website, you may need to submit personal information to register for services, order products, post content or request assistance.
Indirectly. This may be through emails, forms, face-to-face meetings, interviews, registration, attendance at seminars, business cards, online queries and telephone conversations, as well as services through our website and social media channels.
From third parties. For example, we sometimes use third parties to analyse traffic to our website and social media channels. This may involve the use of cookies. Cookies are electronic identifiers that are transferred automatically to your computer via your browser. They allow our systems to save certain details so you are recognised when you visit our website again. This stops you from needing to log in repeatedly, which saves time, and creates a customised website that fits your needs. You may disable or refuse to accept cookies by changing the preferences or settings on your browser. If you choose to disable cookies, you can still use our website, but you won’t be able to use all features.
Why do we collect, hold, use and disclose Personal Information?
DA may collect, hold, use and disclose your Personal Information for the primary purposes for which it was collected such as:
carrying out a registration request.
customising the advertising and content you see.
fulfilling your requests for products and services (including purchases).
improving the content and design of our website and services.
contacting you.
conducting research.
providing anonymous reporting for internal purposes.
contacting users regarding changes to our website or business.
considering the suitability of prospective employees.
DA may also retain the details of purchases and other transactions or payments made with us or affiliates of our organisation, such as PEN Global (Dietitians of Canada).
We may also use or disclose your Personal Information for other purposes to which you consent, or which are required or permitted by law. This may include for a secondary purpose that is related to the purpose for which we collected it, and for which you would reasonably expect us to use or disclose your Personal Information,
Disclosure of Personal Information
It is our policy not to disclose, sell or rent your Personal Information to any individual, business, government entity or third parties except:
to provide products or services you have requested through DA.
in response to a validly issued subpoena, court order or other legal process.
when necessary to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal action.
if you request DA to do so.
anytime authorisation is given to DA to release information about individuals including any request to view an individual’s own information.
for the purpose of providing a public list of names and states/territories of residence to allow confirmation of APD status.
We may also disclose your name, membership details and other personal information to the following parties:
Medicare, Department of Veterans’ Affairs (DVA), National Disability Insurance Agency (NDIA) and private health funds for funding and related purposes.
Commonwealth, State and Territory agencies which receive or investigate health care complaints.
PEN Global (Dietitians of Canada) to enable you to obtain online access to the PEN website.
Healthdirect Australia so that members may be listed on the National Health Services Directory if they have voluntarily added their details to ‘Find an APD’.
If you have opted in to receive advertising and marketing material, we will disclose your email address or physical address to relevant third parties who may contact you for advertising or marketing purposes.
We may publish on our website the name and membership status of any member who has had an adverse finding made against them under DA’s By-Law Complaints and Disciplinary Procedures. We may also publish details of any sanctions imposed on a member under those procedures. DA maintains and publishes details of any person who has been suspended by or expelled from DA.
Setting up user accounts
DA allows users to set up personal accounts to purchase resources or publications from our online library or to participate in our online communities. You can edit your personal information at any time and can ask to have your account removed by emailing membership@dietitiansaustralia.org.au
Correcting your personally identifiable information
Subject to the exceptions set out in the Privacy Act, you may seek access to and correction of your Personal Information by emailing membership@dietitiansaustralia.org.au You will need to verify your identity and specify what you are seeking. If a fee is charged for providing access, you will be advised of the likely cost in advance.
Web statistics and shared data
DA collects and uses web-based information to analyse trends, administer our website, track user movement and to gather broad demographic information for reporting and sponsorship purposes.
Our website uses Google Analytics, a service which transmits website traffic data to Google servers in the United States. Google Analytics does not identify individual users or associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. We use reports provided by Google Analytics to help us understand website traffic and webpage usage.
By using the DA website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner described in Google’s Privacy Policy and for the purposes set out above. You can opt out of Google Analytics if you disable or refuse the cookie, disable JavaScript, or use the opt-out service provided by Google.
Occasionally we may use this information to share with advertising partners, sponsors and/or affiliates. For example, we may tell an advertiser that (x) number of individuals visited a certain area on our website, or that (y) number of men and (z) number of women completed our registration form. However, we will not disclose to these partners, sponsors and/or affiliates anything that could be used to personally identify those individuals.
Third party websites
The DA website contains links to third party websites. DA does not make any representations or warranties in relation to the privacy practices of these websites. We also do not assume any responsibility for the privacy practices or content of these sites. If you visit these websites, they will be governed by their own terms of use (including privacy policies). You are encouraged to be aware when you leave our site and to take reasonable precautions when sharing your Personal Information on third party websites.
Opt-In/Out
You may ’opt in to/out of‘ receiving newsletters, promotional offers and other information from our partners and affiliates. To unsubscribe from external advertising, marketing materials and DA-driven SMS messaging, go to the ‘update your details’ section of the website and edit your personal profile. As DA is required by law to be able to communicate with its members, it’s not possible for current members to opt out of weekly emails and newsletter subscriptions. This is to ensure members don’t miss important information that needs to be communicated on occasion.
Encryption
All user accounts must be accessed with usernames and passwords. You are strongly advised not to share your username and password with any other person. All online payment pages are protected with Secure Socket Layer (‘SSL‘) encryption.
Amendments
DA reserves the right to amend this policy at any time. DA will contact registered users by email and shall also post a notice of changes on our website, when and if the terms of this policy are amended.
Adding your details to accessible website lists
The DA website supports lists which are accessible either to the public (for example, Find an APD) or other members (for example, Find a Mentor). Inclusion in these lists is voluntary and members are responsible for ensuring their details are current and correct.
Disclosure of Personal Information overseas
DA may disclose your Personal Information to the following overseas recipients:
Relevant professional associations such as PEN Global (Dietitians of Canada) to allow members online access to the PEN website (except when we are prevented from doing so due to confidentiality obligations).
Other companies or individuals who provide services or perform functions on our behalf (such as third-party service providers).
Anyone else to whom DA authorised is to disclose it.
Anyone else where we are required or authorised by law to do so.
How we protect your Personal Information
DA works hard to protect your Personal Information at all times. Personal Information is encrypted and stored on secure servers compliant with Australia’s privacy standards. Only authorised personnel can access this database through individualised passwords.
DA emails are not encrypted and authors of email content should be aware not to include personal, sensitive or commercial-in-confidence material. DA emails are notated with a disclaimer explaining the appropriate use and protection of information contained within.
How to make a privacy-related complaint
If you have any questions about privacy-related issues or wish to complain about a breach of your privacy or the handling of your personal information by us, please email ceo@dietitiansaustralia.org.au. Any complaint will be investigated and you will be notified of the decision as soon as practicable, usually within 30 days.
If your concerns are not satisfactorily resolved, you can contact the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner:
GPO Box 5218
Sydney NSW 2001
Email: enquiries@oaic.gov.au
Tel: 1300 363 992
Contact us
Contact us at ceo@dietitiansaustralia.org.au should you have any questions regarding this policy or wish to register any concerns, including potential breaches of your Personal Information.
About usStrategic PlanOrganisational chartBoard of Directors and ExecutivePast PresidentsAnnual ReportReconciliationConstitution and By-lawsCelebrating Member AchievementsAwardsPrizesJosephine (Jo) Rogers AMResearch Grants and ScholarshipsFellows of DA and Advanced APDsProfessional AffiliationsPartnershipsPublic PoliciesAdvertising policiesAlliances and PartnershipsEndorsementMembership fees policyWebsite Link PolicyPrivacy PolicyMembershipWhat Dietitians DoDietitian or Nutritionist?Why Choose an Accredited Practising Dietitian?Your Rights and ResponsibilitiesWhere do Dietitians Work?Information for Healthcare ProfessionalsAPD RolesBecoming a Dietitian in AustraliaAustralian Dietetics Council (ADC)ADC PoliciesAccreditation of Dietetics Education ProgramsAccredited Dietetics Education ProgramsAccreditation Standards and ProcessesRecognition of Dietetic QualificationsDietetic Skills Recognition (DSR)Overseas educated dietitians – Assessment StageDietetic Skills Recognition CriteriaEnglish Language ProficiencyOverseas educated dietitians – Examination stageAppeals ProcessMutual RecognitionMutual Recognition – New ZealandMutual recognition profilesNew Zealand FAQsSkills Migration AssessmentFeesFAQsMembership of DAMaintaining Professional StandardsAccredited Practising Dietitian ProgramHow to Join the APD ProgramDietitian Scope of PracticeNational Competency Standards for DietitiansDietetic Credentialing CouncilProfessional Standards and Code of ConductSupporting Best Practice in DieteticsRegister of Accredited Practising DietitiansAPD registration number FAQExpelled or Suspended MembersDismissal of Ms Jennifer Elliott as a DA memberHow to make a complaintVoice of DietitiansNews RoomMedia ReleasesHot TopicsDietitians Making NewsOur SpokespeopleEditorialChallenging MisinformationDA’s approach to social mediaAdvocacyCall for a New National Nutrition PolicySubmissions2019 Submissions2018 Submissions2017 Submissions2016 Submissions2015 SubmissionsPosition StatementsJoint Position StatementsAdvocacy lettersSmart Eating for a Healthier YouSmart Eating Fast FactsCOVID-19 tips and resourcesNutrition tips and advice during COVID-19Cooking during COVID-19Healthy EatingDietitians’ top (healthy) Christmas gift ideasHealthy eating on a budgetCan I drink alcohol?Health and Wellbeing of Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander peopleI’ve heard I need 2 serves of fruit & 5 serves of vegetables, but what is a serve?I’m tired all the time, should I try a detox diet?The low-down on Paleo – Welcome to our three part series on the Palaeolithic diet.How much exercise do I need to stay healthy?What’s the best type of fat for a healthy heart?Vegan diets: everything you need to knowVegetarian diets – the basicsBreakfast – how to eat brekkie like a boss!Australia’s Healthy Weight WeekThe Australian Dietary GuidelinesChildrenFive ways to help tackle fussy eatingShould we be concerned about a child’s weight?How can I prevent my child from becoming overweight?My child is overweight, what should I do?How can I get my child to eat more fruits and vegetables?What can I put in my child’s lunchbox?How much television can my children watch if I want them to be healthy?Can food additives affect my child’s behaviour?TeensPregnancyNutrition for pregnancyIs there a special diet I should follow while trying to get pregnant?What extra nutrients do I need in pregnancy?What do I need to eat if I’m breastfeeding?Why do pregnant and breastfeeding women need more iodine?Nourishing NutrientsPumping ironAnaemia: my doctor says I need more ironWhy do we need calcium?Carbohydrates – what you need to knowFat: to cut or not to cut, that is the questionWhere do I find saturated fats in foodThe ins and outs of unsaturated fatsShould I be worried about trans fats?All about plant sterols and stanols for cholesterol managementAll about proteinDietary fibre: key for a happy, healthy gutFolate: crucial for women under 50What are the current Nutrient Reference Values (NRVs)?Food and Food Products5 minutes with Matthew Evans – The gap between nourishment and pleasureFast facts: all about avocadosIs organic food better for my health?I don’t eat a lot of fruit and vegetables, should I take a supplement instead?What’s healthier: fresh, frozen or canned foods?Can I eat eggs if I want to be healthy?Are artificial sweeteners safe to eat?Extra Virgin Olive Oil – the latest updateIf I have high cholesterol, can I eat foods with cholesterol?Which type of milk should I drink?Which drinks are the best choice?Top take-away food tipsLegumes: what are they and how can I use them?Why dietitians are nuts about nutsThe facts on coconut oil – is it the best choice?Food waste – a bigger issue that you’d thinkFood LabelsHow are food products regulated in Australia?What are health claims and what do they mean?Making sense of the glycaemic indexWhat does low fat mean?What does low salt mean?MedicalWhat to eat to reduce your risk of gallstonesOrthorexia: The unhealthy side of healthy eatingFODMAPs and IBS: What’s the deal?Can I lower my blood pressure by following a healthy eating plan?How can what I eat improve high blood pressure?Eating less saltThe ins and outs of cholesterolCan I lower my cholesterol through dietary changes?What is coeliac disease?Dental health – looking after your teeth and gumsIs there a diet to prevent and treat cancer?Is there a diet to treat arthritis?The facts on overweight & obesity in AustraliaMy doctor has told me I have impaired glucose tolerance, what should I do?Diabetes – the basicsWhat is insulin resistance?What is metabolic syndrome?What can I do if I am worried that a friend has an eating disorder?What’s the difference between food allergy and food intolerance?Understanding food intolerance & sensitivityA guide to irritable bowel syndromeMy doctor said I’ve got diverticular disease, what should I eat?Helping to ease the pain of gout through dietUnderstanding lactose intoleranceAre you underweight?Is malnutrition an issue in Australia?Malnutrition – who is at risk and things to considerThings to consider with haemochromatosisWeight ManagementWeight loss goals other than the scalesSmart eating for weight managementHow to spot a dodgy weight loss dietAre carbohydrates fattening?How can I choose the right weight loss plan for me?How can I stay motivated to maintain a healthy diet for weight loss?What should I do to lose weight?I need to gain weight, what should I eat?Smart Eating RecipesEvents and MarketplaceCentre for Advanced LearningAged CareBariatric SurgeryCounsellingDiabetesEating DisordersFood Allergy and IntoleranceNutrition SupportPaediatricsSports NutritionPEN – Practice-based Evidence in Nutrition®Advertise with usFind a LocumPublications & ResourcesResources available for purchaseNutrition & Dietetics JournalEditorial BoardFor AuthorsFor ReviewersAssociate Editor CentreNutrition & Dietetics Journal AppLectures in Honour & Obituaries
